(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
[Fate Chooses You]
[Episode 22]
How about
we treat Master Lu to a meal?
I'm afraid not. That's too much trouble.
But we insist.
A real gentleman knows
when to return a favor.
Please wait a moment, Master Lu.
Food will be ready soon.
Let's go!
Sure.
Go then.
Move!
Quick.
Let's go.
Go.
Is it all?
Nothing more?
You insisted on treating him to a meal
after he declined to be paid.
How can we afford food
and wine for him now?
I acted on impulse.
This is all my fault.
What should we do now?
I'll go make money
by writing letters for people.
I can do that too.
I can even write poems.
Me too.
-I can also do that.
-So can I.
Count me in as well.
But is there enough time?
I...
Then what do you suggest?
Master Rust-Sword!
Are you crazy or what,
for targeting me?
-Master Rust-Sword.
-Master Rust-Sword!
Sorry for the rudeness.
What are you doing?
Are you robbing me in broad daylight?
Just lend us some money!
Stop it now, or I'll fight back.
Consider it a loan to us!
Yes, yes, just a loan.
My arm...
My arm is broken!
Are you alright?
Faking an injury, huh?
Get up now.
D-Don't make me slap you.
Lord of Rust-Sword, this is an emergency.
We'll pay you back later.
Let go of my master!
I'll beat you up!
This is adults' business.
Stay out of it, kiddo.
I'm not a kid.
Just don't butt in.
Let go of me!
It's here! Here!
Quick!
Hurry!
Pull harder!
We will surely pay you back later.
No!
My money!
We'll definitely pay you back!
My money...
You bunch of robbers,
I'm going to kill you!
You'll all be dead meat!
My money...
What's going on outside?
Nothing.
They're just horsing around.
My money!
Come on.
Have some tea.
This is mint tea.
It reduces internal heat.
Try it, please.
Did I put in enough salt?
What you put in was sugar.
Make the fire bigger.
Got it.
Stop nibbling on that carrot.
G-Go fetch some firewood.
Zhanying.
Master Rust-Sword,
come drink with us later.
What a feast today.
There's wine, meat,
and vegetables.
Master Lu,
Immortal Xin,
don't stand on ceremony.
Be the first ones to eat.
Please.
Don't rabbits only eat plants?
But I've become a rabbit demon now.
Why can't I have meat?
Alright!
Let's eat!
Come on.
One piece for each of you.
No fighting needed.
Thank you.
We bought this
from Li's Smoked Chicken,
a century-old shop in the Phoenix City.
The taste is amazing.
Nonsense, old man.
You've never tasted it.
Little demon,
how do you know I've never tasted it?
You can't afford it, can you?
To prove yourself,
why not tell us
if the drumsticks are salty or spicy?
Salty, of course.
Mr. Lu,
try one.
Let's see if this old man is correct.
I'm not hungry now.
An,
taste it for me.
Thanks.
You should eat it, Master.
Way to read the room.
I'll take this drumstick,
but not you as a disciple.
An,
you can have mine.
Thank you.
Everyone, eat up.
The food's getting cold.
-Hurry!
-Dig in!
Thank you for your aid
along the journey,
Master Lu, Immortal Xin.
If it hadn't been for your help,
we would probably
have failed to make it
to the Phoenix City alive.
You even gave us two precious paintings
as gifts.
We doubt if we will ever be able
to repay such kindness.
Come on, everyone.
Let's propose a toast
to them both.
A toast to you both.
Cheers.
Come on, let's eat.
I also protected you along the way.
Why only toast them and not me?
Because we hired your service.
You hired my service?
Then give me my pay.
The journey was a bitter experience
for me.
Instead of making money,
I even lost quite a sum.
Not bitter at all.
There's sugar in the food.
It tastes sweet.
Still, I paid for...
Lord of Rust-Sword, as a single man,
you seem quite eager to make money.
Are you trying to get a wife?
I have no family, so you don't
need to offer any betrothal gifts.
Do you think I'd make a good wife for you?
No, I don't think so.
I don't plan to get married.
Besides,
I'm not interested in those older than me.
But you're of age. Why not start a family?
I just haven't met anyone I love.
What a coincidence.
Neither have I.
An!
Have a drink with Zhanying now.
Zhanying,
come on.
Let's drink.
Chen Fen,
I've always been curious.
Why were you given
such a jinxed name as "Fen"?
I'm from the Chen clan in Qinling—
a long line of tomb raiders.
My family have been raiding tombs
for generations.
About 300 years ago,
South Xiang King, Li Xiang,
was dying of a severe illness.
He took the advice of a ghost cultivator
and decided to build a grand mausoleum
for himself and set up
a Feng Shui Formation,
attempting in vain to be revived
in 500 years
following the Path of Ghosts.
After the mausoleum was completed,
in order to keep
its location secret,
Li Xiang had his personal guards
kill all the craftsmen
who helped build it.
Unexpectedly,
on the guards' way back,
they were trapped by a heavy downpour.
Residents of the Chen Village
kindly helped them.
However, Li Xiang, the unscrupulous ruler,
had the Chen Village
nearly annihilated afterwards,
just in order to conceal
everything about the mausoleum.
My great-great-grandfather
was a child at that time.
He luckily survived.
Later, he focused on
the study of tomb-raiding arts,
with the determination
to avenge the Chen Village.
Then why did you come to the Phoenix City
instead of searching for the mausoleum?
I did find that place.
But the traps inside work with rather
complex mechanisms.
I couldn't gain access.
So,
I came here
for the Unparalleled Secret Magic
that might give me a solution.
It's very tenacious of you.
But what if you can't find
a solution this time?
If that happens, my sons
will carry on the mission.
And if my sons fail,
my grandsons will continue.
No matter what,
my resolution to dig up
that vile old man's tomb and hold him back
from immortality will not waver!
Why are you all giving me this look?
You've heard this story before,
haven't you?
I am shocked every time
I hear about this king's atrocities.
At this very moment,
I'd like to recite a poem.
Enjoy the meal, scholar.
Great scholar,
back in Wei County,
didn't you say
you'd take the imperial exam?
Don't get me started.
I did reach the capital.
But I found that among the exam takers,
half were from families
connected to immortal sects,
and four out of ten
were rich kids with strings to pull.
Young lads from poor families like me
amounted to only a few.
That day,
the person in front of me
was cheating
with the immortal art of observation.
I reported him,
but the invigilator
kicked me out instead.
In a fit of anger,
I left the capital.
None of those from immortal sects
are good.
Immortal Xin,
his comment is not directed at you.
Have I said it wrong?
Those from immortal sects
once set up a formation in Dahuang Valley
to draw
spiritual energy from the earth veins
for their cultivation,
which only ended up
exploding the earth veins
and causing half the valley to collapse.
As a county constable at that time,
I was transferred there
to handle the aftermath,
along with over ten fellows
who had been through
life-and-death moments with me.
The spiritual energy there
was just bizzarre.
Like poisonous fog,
it found a way into our bodies.
Shortly after,
all my fellows died.
I was the only one
who survived.
Look at me now—
all messed up and miserable!
I'm entitled to hatred, aren't I?
Although I came to North Xiang
with Wushuang Society members,
my thoughts are different
from theirs.
They have too big an ambition.
I don't quite understand.
But I was told
that as long as I came here,
I would be given a sword,
which could
help me pierce the hearts of immortals.
Which immortal sect set up that formation?
Who assigned you to handle
the aftermath?
It was the Holy Fire Sect
that set up the formation.
The one who assigned me to that task
was Song Qingsong,
the magistrate of Xuzhou County.
The Holy Fire Sect
is one of the Twelve Immortal Sects.
It's managed by Master Yuntuzi,
a superior cultivator at the Void Stage.
He's a hundred years old now.
In the Battle of Pinghu,
he fought off dozens
of War Demons on his own
and saved the people of an entire city.
He had 31 direct disciples,
all of whom died protecting Xuzhou,
except two—
they lost arms or legs
and were incapacitated.
Almost all the core disciples
of the Holy Fire Sect
died in that battle.
Yuntuzi was the only one left
with the ability to support the sect.
He was already old at that time.
Before his final hour arrived,
he had to absorb spiritual energy
and sacrifice his own body
to set up a protective formation
so as to secure the lives of Xuzhou people
and to maintain the prestige
of the Holy Fire Sect
for it to last for generations.
How was it wrong?
So what if the story you told
is true?
I was indeed injured, wasn't I?
My friends lost their lives,
didn't they?
I'm not denying your suffering.
I just have one question.
Are immortal sects
really completely evil in your eyes?
You keep saying
how immortal sects try to kill you
and persecute you.
But have you forgotten?
It was these immortal sects
that courageously
fought the War Demons.
It was also these immortal sects
that protected the people.
Mortals outnumber immortals
by a hundredfold, even a thousandfold.
But in the Battle of Pinghu,
the number of casualties in immortal sects
was almost the same as that of mortals.
Immortal sects bore the brunt at war.
Now that peace has been restored,
you're accusing immortal sects
of oppressing and persecuting you.
Shouldn't the contribution
of immortal sects be remembered?
Immortal Xin,
please don't be mad.
He was just drunk and rambling.
That day, you asked me
if I could guarantee
that all disciples of immortal sects
thought the same way I did.
Right now, I'd like
to ask you a question too.
Can you guarantee
that every human has a good nature?
Oppressing the people,
slaughtering mortals,
and committing murder—
humans and authorities are engaged
in these crimes as well, aren't they?
I really don't understand
why the immortal sects
that have shed blood and sacrificed
are described
as completely evil by you lot!
Those from immortal sects
haven't gone far.
You could be easily spotted
by rushing out like this.
Sheng, where on earth are you going?
Was I being too harsh just now?
Did I scare them all?
Arguments are inevitable
among people holding different stances.
In fact, I know
why you went livid.
For one thing, you were trying to defend
immortal sects.
For another,
part of you felt what those people said
was correct.
I once saw a tower ship
in the desert.
It was a huge vessel.
There was no water around.
It must've flown there.
I couldn't think of
any other way for it to reach North Xiang.
So, I'm sure what they said
is partly right,
and definitely partly wrong.
But actually,
the problem is not about
whether immortal sects are good or bad.
Nor is it about
whether the Human Race is good or bad.
Craftsmanship has brought hope to humans,
and an opportunity
for them to possess power
so as not to rely on others anymore.
However, immortal sects
have always
provided protection for the Human Race.
They naturally need the latter's support.
Therefore, immortal sects
will not allow humans
to slip from their control
and step on a different path.
Consider it this way:
immortal sects and humans
are in a tug of war
over the control of this world.
Does this thought
make you feel better?
No.
I believe there's a right and wrong
to everything.
Right, wrong, good, and evil must exist.
People are just
whitewashing or glossing over them
with certain things.
However, now,
I still can't see anything through
or figure anything out.
I've always been confused
since I joined an immortal sect.
Look,
if we're banned from interfering
with mundane matters,
then what is
the point of cultivation at all?
Back in Chongling Valley,
I was already baffled
about how things went so bad
between immortal sects and humans.
What's going on now
puzzles me even more.
Just like you said,
maybe we should wait and observe.
Keep moving forward,
and time will give you an answer.
Anything wrong?
Such weak breath support.
Is he playing a funeral march?
He is, after all,
Father's most favored son.
Old Crip,
show him some respect.
Most favored son?
He knows nothing but cliché tunes.
With that little talent of his,
he shows off all the time
in front of Father.
You...
You have no shame!
Show off how?
Elaborate on it.
Oh, I get it.
He stays by the Soul Lamp all day long
and plays the flute non-stop.
Even the deaf could hear him.
Bah! You're spewing filth!
You'd better stop slandering my brother.
Little Cicada,
I'm a brother of yours too.
Why do you never defend me like that?
Do you...
actually
enjoy this tune?
You're here yet you won't show up.
Why?
Do you plan to stay hidden forever?
What's the rush?
I caught two naughty kids
last night.
It took me nearly a whole night
to snap their heads off.
Xingye,
you asked me to come here.
It had better be for something important.
Is everyone here now?
Brother,
Wei hasn't arrived yet.
He offended me on the way,
so I killed him.
Impressive.
You had the gall to kill him.
Aren't you afraid
that Father will blame you?
Wei blinded one of my eyes last year!
Father said
that if he dared to mess with me again,
I had the right to kill him!
Alright, cut the crap.
Why did you
require my presence here?
I got a message from Father,
saying that Gui's killer was found.
That person is in the Phoenix City now.
Father wants all of us to go there,
catch her,
and bring her back to Qianyan Cave.
Now that Father knows where she is,
why must he make us go there
instead of taking action himself?
Isn't it too much trouble?
How dare you question Father's orders!
Still bickering, huh?
The killer is said to be
a female cultivator
from the Central Plains.
What is her cultivation level?
The Foundation Establishment Stage.
The female cultivator
they are talking about
must be my senior sister.
Does it mean I am not
the one who that old man is after?
How is
a mere Foundation Establishment cultivator
worthy of
the joint efforts of all of us?
It is pointed out in Father's message
that despite
her mediocre cultivation strength,
this woman is accompanied
by a Nascent Soul master
with amazing powers
and smart strategies.
In case of accidents,
Father would like us to work as a team.
A Nascent Soul cultivator?
I can't take on this task then.
Seeing how weak I am,
they might capture me
and try to hurt me.
I won't be able to fight back
in that case.
Little Cicada,
you can't go either.
You...
According to Father's message,
all of us must go there.
Whoever kills that female cultivator
will be rewarded
by Father.
Fine.
That being the case,
we'd better not waste any more time.
Let's set off!
Go!
The female cultivator they are looking for
is your senior sister.
Will you go save her?
There are six of them.
Two are at the Golden Core Stage,
and four at the Nascent Soul Stage.
They're all stronger than you and me.
Sheng,
you need my help.
Think it through.
I was born with bad luck.
Misfortune falls on
everyone close to me.
Are you sure you'll stick with me?
Yes.
Then keep your mouth shut
and follow me.
They are back.
Hurry.
Look sincere. Stand straight.
No problem.
Immortal Xin, please be seated.
Thanks.
Master Lu,
Immortal Xin,
on behalf of my fellows
in Wushuang Society,
I'd like to apologize to you
for the previous remarks.
Have this drink,
and we'll still be friends.
Did anything happen just now?
No.
Nothing happened at all.
Right?
Right.
Nothing happened.
-Right!
-Nothing happened.
Everyone, sit down.
Let's have a drink together.
Sure.
Come on.
Of course.
Cheers!
What's the fun in just drinking?
Rust-Sword, little buddy.
How about I sing you a song?
It's a folk song from my hometown.
Men sing it when they propose marriage.
Women sing it
when they meet the men they're into.
-Great!
-Go ahead!
No, no, please don't.
Men at 18 are like blooms.
Zhanying,
please show some mercy
and try not to destroy a bloom.
You...
You can sing for him!
Or if you have to,
sing for Lu!
He's older than me.
As it happens,
I'm only into you!
-Lord of Rust-Sword, don't run away!
-Don't go!
Freeze!
Stop running!
An, An!
Still running, huh?
Zhanying,
l-let me
propose a toast to you.
Alright.
Everyone, if you don't mind,
let me sing for you.
Great!
Go ahead.
♪ Peerless Goddess Wushuang,
unmatched in all the world ♪
♪ Exquisite tower ships
soar across the heavens ♪
♪ Within her wondrous halls,
thousands find their place ♪
♪ Cannons and blades alike—
unrivaled in battle ♪
-Bravo!
Come on.
Drink up.
Hold still.
Go!
Move.
Keep up with me.
What is this place?
The Purgatory,
where I grew up.
Wait!
I owe you a favor now.
This is it.
It's cooler outside.
You drank so much wine
in that stuff room.
You'd certainly feel hot in there.
That said, this place is still much cooler
than Xutuo City.
This is the Chill Street.
Of course it's cooler here.
What's the story behind the name?
This used to be a wasteland.
Passing merchants
liked to rest and cool off here.
So it developed into
what it is today.
Ahead is Xilian Range,
consisting of high hills
that stretch for thousands of miles
and block most of the heat.
Due to that,
this area is much cooler
than any other place.
Over time,
people started calling it
the Chill Street.
There are perks to living a long life.
You get to see everything.
Is that a compliment?
It certainly is.
Have you been
here before?
Yes, once.
But it was
a long time ago.
We have nothing to do tonight anyway.
Why don't you tell me about it?
Sure.
Let me take you to a place.
This is it.
[Market Quarter Scenes]
Did you paint all of this?
When I was in the Phoenix City before,
I used to drink in this very tavern.
At that time,
under the influence of wine,
I drew this, the Market Quarter Scenes.
Unfortunately,
my flesh hadn't been replaced by then,
so I couldn't identify colors
or depict
the entirety of the mortal world.
When I was learning to paint,
my tutors at the painting hall
always compared life to a scroll.
They often described life
to be
"colorful"
or "vibrantly colored."
Since I couldn't tell colors apart,
I was never able to draw
a complete drawing.
But your ink wash painting is already
masterful and beyond compare.
This is not enough.
It's far from enough.
Not only do I yearn to see the world
as it is,
I also want to enjoy
everything it has to offer.
I'd hate for my life to be incomplete
like this painting is.
I hope to fill my life with warmth
and colors.
I wish
I could live a fulfilled life
like a mortal.
I hate to get hysterical
and thirsty for blood again.
I want to learn etiquette
and to tell right from wrong.
I long to see
the myriad colors in this world.
I also crave
to experience every feeling
that ties me to this world,
be it pain,
agony,
resentment,
or sorrow.
I want to have a sense of taste as well.
I wish I could taste every delicacy
in this world.
If that day really comes,
I'd like to hire
the most expensive restaurant
in the capital
to serve me the best cuisine
and the strongest wine,
so I can get drunk
and have a good sleep.
♪ Let strong wine carry me into
drunken nights till midnight ♪
♪ Let my soul blaze in brilliant colors ♪
♪ Let the agony of a thousand cuts ♪
♪ Stand as proof that I have lived ♪
♪ Let me taste a life of flesh and blood
in full ♪
♪ Let me savor the many flavors
of the mortal world ♪
♪ Let me face the world's
warmth and cold alike ♪
♪ To live and perish with it,
daring to go mad, daring to dream ♪
♪ Let strong wine carry me into
drunken nights till midnight ♪
♪ Let my soul blaze in brilliant colors ♪
♪ Let the agony of a thousand cuts ♪
♪ Stand as proof that I have lived ♪
After so many years,
this painting
is finally complete.
♪ Let me taste a life of flesh and blood
in full ♪
Your life will also
become complete little by little.
♪ Let me savor the many flavors
of the mortal world ♪
♪ Let me face the world's
warmth and cold alike ♪
♪ To live and perish with it,
daring to go mad, daring to dream ♪
♪ Don't live in vain,
have a pleasant journey of life ♪
That painting
was made by Master Buquan!
You must pay for damaging it.
Guards, take them down!
Run!
Stop there!
Stop!
Freeze!
Don't you have
any questions for me?
Many, actually.
But I think
you will tell me everything
when you feel like doing so.
If you don't,
it's of no use to ask.
I have to say you're brilliant.
I've learned a lesson or two
after spending so much time with you.
That day, you asked me
if I felt pain from injuries.
I am not made of wood or stones.
Of course I feel pain when I'm injured.
But compared with the suffering
I experienced in Qianyan Cave,
a sword wound through the chest
could barely amount to anything.
Were you attacked
by those people in the woods?
What exactly
do they have to do with you?
Stop running!
Freeze!
Halt!
There they are!
-Stop running!
-Catch up with them!
They've gone far.
Oh right.
In your opinion,
to get rid of
the Punishment of the Five Deficiencies
why would the War Demons choose
to plant Jianmu Tree
and attempt to ascend to heaven,
over the solution you proposed?
Power is like poison.
One can't live without it when one has it.
I think maybe
I just see things
differently than my fellows.
In their eyes,
reincarnating as humans
is a process of losing power.
But in my eyes,
it is a critical part
of completing my life.
Actually,
I am of mixed ancestry.
My mother was a War Demon.
But my father
was a human.
How did a War Demon and a human
end up a couple?
They met each other
when all gods disappeared,
and the human world
was struck by ceaseless war.
My mother fell in love with my father.
For him,
she ran away from home,
abandoned her responsibility,
retreated to the wilderness,
and gave birth to me.
I suppose your mother
must have loved you
and your father a lot.
She did, originally.
But unfortunately,
my father was a spy for the Human Race.
He approached my mother
just to gather intelligence
about War Demons.
As my mother found out the truth,
she got furious
and killed my father and his fellows.
Then,
she left me in blazing flames.
That fire
almost burned off
all my skin.
The silver lining was, I got new skin
and finally some good sleep.
After that,
I started roaming the streets.
I couldn't turn to my mother
at the War Demons' place.
Humans saw me as enemy.
At that time, I was all alone.
There was no room
for me in this vast world.
So I had to conceal my identity
and look for my father.
What happened then?
Then, I met my master.
You had a master?
Her name was Duan Xianyin.
She had been in seclusion
at Liubo Temple for years.
Very few people knew about her.
She took me in as a disciple,
taught me to read and write,
and instructed me on magic techniques.
After that,
I began wandering in the human world.
Because my lifespan
is longer than mortals',
and my appearance doesn't age easily,
I had to frequently
change my name and identity.
At first, I worked in the Imperial Palace
where I met Su Taiyi.
Later on,
being deprived of power,
I took Su Taiyi away with me
from the palace.
Then, I met Mrs. Li.
The Landlady of the Safe Haven Inn?
Yes.
After that, I got very bored,
so I decided to be a hero
in the martial world.
The many years of adventuring in it
opened my eyes
to the fun
and the tight interpersonal connection
in this community.
That made my desire to live as a mortal
become stronger and stronger.
Then I joined the army
and worked as a magistrate.
What next?
Next,
I met you
and died a death by 1,000 cuts.
You know all about
what happened after that.
But I've lost those memories.
I can't recall anything.
When I see Chu Ying,
I will definitely have him
restore your memories right away.
I grew up in Qianyan Cave.
I was a slave and servant
living a worse life than an animal's.
The people here often
tested drugs on me.
The master of Qianyan Cave is Xia Xuanzi.
With that pretty face of his,
he looks like a young man.
But he is
the most vicious of all.
You've heard about
the Crazy Taoist's prophecies, right?
Yes.
A destructive disaster
will befall the world.
Those who are born on September 9th
will be saviors of the world.
Actually,
he left three prophecies back then.
The first two are for the people.
The third one
is for Xia Xuanzi.
Those two prophecies of yours
have caused quite a stir
in the martial world.
Everyone says you have a brilliant mind
that enables you to see
the will of heaven.
In fact, I'm curious.
Did you figure out
why I caught you today?
You are just wondering
when you will leap to a higher level
and become a divinity
after being stuck at the Void Stage
for many years.
You will never become a divinity.
Trouble follows careless words.
Immortal Master, watch your tongue.
Xia Xuanzi of Qianyan Cave,
I know what you're capable of.
That day when my spirit roamed the heaven,
I got a glimpse
of three future happenings.
I already told the world
about the first two.
The third one was left unsaid on purpose,
because I was waiting for you.
Waiting for me?
The third prophecy
concerns you.
[Crazy Taoist, from Dongting Mountain]
That is, one of your decendents
will become a divinity.
Perhaps obsessed about
becoming a divinity,
Xia Xuanzi started
having children like crazy.
He believed
that only males could be divinities.
So he used his power
to make women give birth
to boys only.
He then discarded the mothers
and kept the babies.
He would even place Gu bugs
in our bodies
so he could manipulate us.
That Gu is called the Bonding Curse.
The cursed ones will share
the same fate and feelings.
I fell victim to it too.
He connected our lives
with the Gu bugs
and tortured us all day long
whenever he felt displeased.
I was hurt by needles, fire,
and boiling oil.
He would even tear off our limbs
and pull out our tendons.
Yet he would keep us alive
so as to make us do his bidding
and to torture us repeatedly.
But even under such conditions,
no one in Qianyan Cave
dared to fight back.
What was more hilarious
was that those sons of his
all grew up to be just like him.
I had no idea
you once lived
such a miserable life.
Luckily,
I managed to escape.
I crossed the desert alone
and reached the Central Plains.
Then, I met my senior sister.
That was how I survived.
Now, Xia Xuanzi
attempts to kill her.
I did fear him in the past,
but I don't anymore.
I will kill whoever tries
to hurt my senior sister.
Be careful.
Won't it be a shame
to destroy
these two beautiful faces?
You really are good-looking.
If it weren't for
my father's order to kill you,
I really couldn't bring myself to do so.
Your father?
What is your relationship with Xia Xuanzi?
How dare you call my father by his name!
You must have a death wish!
Brother,
you go catch that girl.
Just let me deal with
this tough nut to crack.
Old Crip,
are you just going to watch?